<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog of Tom Lowndes</title>
    <link>http://tomlowndes.co.uk/blog/</link>
    <description>Blog feed of Tom Lonwdes. All posts written by Tom Lowndes.</description>
    <pubDate>2013</pubDate>

    
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Making a new website</title>
          <pubDate>2013-04-27T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://tomlowndes.github.io/post/github-jekyll/</link>
          <guid>http://tomlowndes.github.io/post/github-jekyll/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;white&quot; src=&quot;http://www.tomlowndes.co.uk/images/blog/gitjekyll.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Github + Jekyll&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, so after a hard few days, version 1.1 of my github / jekyll hybred website is up and running. The main bulk of code was written by a few other people and found on github, I have just tweaked it to my liking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Github hosting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to host my website on github due to it being a relativly easy method to do, you write the html, css and .md files in you native coding application (mine being Sublime Text 2.) Then commit and push those files to Github using a program like Github / tower or by using the terminal, which is explained step by step on the Github site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Rolling back&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing about coding a website to live on Github is that if you commit a change then notice that it didn't work then you can roll back to an earyler commit, saving time of finding the problem by scrubbing through all the code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also allows you to code offline on any computer by being able to download the Github repository, which I have kept in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://dropbox.com/&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; folder, change files and then once happy with those changes push it up to the love site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;URL Problems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem that I have stuggled with is getting the url tomlowndes.co.uk to point to the github files so at the moment to acsess the site it is blog.tomlowndes.co.uk but once this is fixed I feel that the results are very promising.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
    
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>